Sumo...
（ナレーション）“相撲”…
Battles waged in a ring by those wearing
mawashi belts since ancient times in Japan.
土俵上で 廻(まわ)しのみを身につけ 戦う
日本古来の武道であり—
It is one of the few combat sports
without weight classes.
数少ない“無差別級”の格闘技
Thus, larger and heavier student sumo
wrestlers have a distinct advantage.
ゆえに 学生相撲においても—
“大きく”“重く”ある者が
絶対優位
Among them...
中でも
横綱候補と期待される者には…
Those with the potential to
reach the rank of yokozuna...
receive the name of a sword from the
national treasures as their moniker.
国宝級の刀剣に なぞらえた—
二つ名が与えられた
Bout 1
"National Treasure Onimaru Kunitsuna"
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）ンンッ… グッ…
ブハッ！
I hate crowded trains.
満員電車は苦手じゃ…　うん？
（男性）ウ〜ン…
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）ンンッ…
（男性）アアッ！
（火ノ丸）そこまでじゃ
That's enough.
Let's get off at the next station.
次の駅で降りてもらおうかのぅ
What do you think you're doing?
And at your age!
（火ノ丸）
ええ年して 何しとんじゃ？
Wh-What proof do you have?!
（男性）
しょ… 証拠はあんのかよ？
（火ノ丸）ハン！
ワシの位置からは丸見えだったわい
From where I was standing,
I could see you clearly.
Remember, God is watching.
こんなマネして…
お天道(てんとう)さまは見とるぞ
Please let me through!
（駅員）ちょっと 通して
Oh, station attendant!
The molester is over here.
おう 駅員さん　こっちじゃ
（火ノ丸）痴漢は この…
（駅員）なんて格好してるんだ 君
Why are you dressed like that?!
あっ ちょ…
いやいや 痴漢は こっちじゃて！
Wait, no! The molester is right...
Trying to frighten girls
by not wearing pants!
（駅員）そんな格好で
女の子を驚かそうなんて！
No, I'm going to check out a new school,
（火ノ丸）いや これは
これから学校見学行くんで—
so I wanted to make a good impression!
（火ノ丸）ビシッと決めようと…
（千鶴子）アア…
（火ノ丸）ウヘ〜ッ…
I wanted to join their morning practice,
but it's already after noon.
朝稽古に参加しようと
思っとったのに もう昼じゃ
I got off one station too soon,
so I'm not sure where I am.
１つ前の駅で降りたもんで
道が よく分からん
And this map Kirihito drew for me
is no help at all.
その上 桐仁(きりひと)の
描いてくれた地図が これじゃ…
Here
おお あれか！
That must be it!
え〜っと…　正面は あっちかのぅ
The front gate must be over there.
ウワッ！
（小関(おぜき)）ンンッ…
（小関）ハァ…
Oh, you're practicing!
（火ノ丸）稽古中じゃったか！
（小関）えっ？　誰？
Would you mind if I joined you?
ワシも交ぜてくれんかのぅ？
Um...
（火ノ丸）よっととと…
（火ノ丸）
おお！　さすが名門 石神(いしがみ)高校
That's the powerhouse Ishigami High School for ya!
They have sumo rings outside, too!
道場の外にも土俵があるとは
The bale looks like it's a
fire hose filled with dirt.
俵は 消防ホースに
土を入れて作ってあるんか
（土をたたく音）
土もカッチカチじゃ！
And the dirt is packed tight!
U-Um, who are you?
（小関）あ… あの…　君は？
Oh, pardon me.
うん？
あっ こりゃ とんだ失礼してもうた
I got a little excited when I
saw someone in a mawashi belt.
廻し姿を見つけて
ちと舞い上がってしまってのぅ
My apologies.
申し訳ない　ワシゃ まだ中３です
I'm still a third-year middle schooler.
I came to check out this school
because it has a sumo club!
相撲部がある この学校へ
見学に来ました
My name is Ushio Hinomaru.
名を 潮(うしお)火ノ丸といいます
In order to reach yokozuna,
the highest rank in sumo,
のちに 大相撲の最高位
横綱へ至る道として—
I must become the strongest
high school sumo wrestler!
高校相撲の頂点を
取らんとする者じゃ！
Y-Yokozuna?
よ… 横綱？
What's your name?
あんたの名は？
I'm Ozeki from the sumo club.
（小関）俺？　相撲部の小関
You must be passionate to
be practicing during lunch.
（火ノ丸）
昼休みにも自主練とは熱心じゃのぅ
Can we have a bout?
（火ノ丸）どうじゃ？　ワシと一番
（小関）ちょちょちょ…
W-W-Wait... What are you doing?
いきなり何する…　あっ…
Sorry, could you get my bag?
（火ノ丸）すまんがのぅ
カバン取ってくれんか？
My mawashi belt is in it.
廻しが入ってんじゃ
Sure...
（小関）
ああ　…て君 ここで着替えるの？
Wait, are you going to change here?
I don't mind.
（火ノ丸）ワシは平気じゃ
（小関）
こいつ 相当 鍛えてるじゃん
He's trained a lot.
何だよ？　あの無数の傷
Where did he get all those scars?
Shall we get to it?
（火ノ丸）じゃ やりましょうか
（小関）あっ うん
Oh, sure.
何だよ？　その圧
What's that pressure?
O-Okay, then...
よ〜し…
Spirit!
（火ノ丸）はっきよい！
（小関）ンンッ…　グッ…
（火ノ丸）どうしたんじゃ？
What's wrong?
Is that all you've got?
こんなもんか？
ンンッ…　この…
Why, you...
（小関）ナメるな〜！
（火ノ丸）おお
Don't underestimate me!
（小関）オリャー！
（火ノ丸）オリャ！
（小関）ウッ！　ハァハァ…
フゥ…
Ow...
いっててて…　すごいね
You're really good.
You're good, too.
あんたも なかなかやるのぅ
You said your name is Ushio-kun, right?
（小関）潮君っていったっけ？
You're so strong, I'm surprised I haven't
heard your name at the tournaments before.
これだけ強かったら
大会で 名前聞きそうなんだけどな
（火ノ丸）
あ〜 まあ いろいろあってのぅ
Well, there's a story behind that.
I've never really been
in many official bouts.
公式戦はロクに出とらんのじゃ
Just a few in elementary school.
小学校では
そこそこ鳴らしたんじゃがのぅ
I see.
（小関）そうなんだ？
Maybe I shouldn't have said anything.
なんか
聞いちゃいけなかったかな…
That's why I want to
enroll at this school.
（火ノ丸）そんでもって
この高校に入ろうと思っとって
Sorry I couldn't make
the morning practice.
残念ながら 朝稽古には
間に合わんかったんじゃが…
Morning practice?
朝稽古？　ていうか
ウチの部に入ってくれるの？
Wait, you're joining the club?
Of course!
もちろんじゃ
Really?
（小関）ホントに？
（火ノ丸）おう
Yeah.
ハハハッ！
信じられない ウチに入部だなんて
I can't believe it! A new club member!
It's not that big a deal.
大げさじゃのぅ
いやいやいや！
大げさじゃないって
No, it totally is!
How about we go see the dojo?
そんじゃ 早速
道場のほうを見せてもらおうかのぅ
Um, well... are you sure you want to?
いや あの… その…
どうしても見る？
Well, you'll find out sooner or later.
（小関）まあ
いずれ知られちまうことだから…
オッ…　誰か部員がいるのぅ
こんちは！
The other members are inside!
Hello!
（小関）ハァ…
West
Fight with all your might
That's how it is.
こういうわけなんだ
I heard there were a lot of
delinquents at this school.
ヤンキーの多い学校とは
聞いとったが…
Who are you? What're you doing here?
（舟木）
何だ お前！　何か用か こら！
Who's the shrimp?
（西郷）何だ？　このチビ
Ozeki!
（舟木）小関！
（小関）はい！
Yes!
Who gave you permission to come here?!
（舟木）
誰に断って 入ってきたんだよ？
Oh, I, um...
（小関）いや あの… その…
Quit your muttering!
（西郷）
ゴニョゴニョ言ってんな こら！
Hey, pick that up.
（火ノ丸）おい 拾え
（舟木）ああ？
The dojo is hallowed ground.
神聖な道場じゃぞ　汚すんじゃねえ
You're not to defile it.
拾えと言うとるんじゃ！
I said to pick it up!
う… 潮君
U-Ushio-kun...
Watch your mouth, shrimp!
口の利き方に気をつけろ チビ！
Don't look down on me, shrimp.
見下ろすな チビが！
What are you guys howling about?
（佑真(ゆうま)）何わめいてんだ？　お前ら
（西郷）佑真さん
Yuma-san!
I thought someone was here for a fight.
（佑真）
どっかのバカが殴り込みにでも
来たのかと思ったらよ
How about you tell me
what's going on, Ozeki.
どういうことか説明してくれよ
小関
ヒイッ！　あっ その…
W-We...
It was this shrimp!
（舟木）このチビっす！
He came in and started a fight!
こいつが粋がって
ケンカ吹っかけてきやがったんスよ
俺 あいつに胸倉…
（殴る音）
I'll give him a good punch.
（倒れる音）
だから ナメられるんだよ
That's why you're an easy target.
Shrimp...
チビ
このバカが言ってたことは本当か？
Is what that idiot said true?
Yeah, it is.
（火ノ丸）ああ そうじゃ
（佑真）覚悟はできてんだろうな？
I hope you're ready for this, then.
（火ノ丸）
ハァ…　暇な連中じゃのぅ
You have a lot of time on your hands.
It's stupid.
（火ノ丸）くだらねえ
（佑真）ああ？
How about you all do some sumo?
いっそのこと
お前らも相撲やらんか？
It's a lot of fun!
楽しいぞ　相撲
You mean when two fat guys hug each other?
デブとデブが
裸で抱き合うのがか？
（火ノ丸）ああ？
（佑真）おう やんのか？
What?
Oh, you wanna fight?
Um...
（小関）ダメだって！
あの…　ごめんなさい 違うんです
I'm sorry. We don't.
Stay out of this, biggest
coward at Dachi High.
ジャマすんな ダチ高一の腰抜け
（火ノ丸）ダチ高？
Dachi High?
He says he'll join the
sumo club next year.
こいつは来年 相撲部に入るって
言ってくれてるんです
What's that about Dachi High?
（火ノ丸）ダチ高って何じゃ？
We need to go, Ushio-kun.
ほら 行くよ 潮君！
Hey, what was that about Dachi High?
（火ノ丸）
なあ ダチ高って何じゃ？
What will you do, Yuma-san?
どうします？　佑真さん
I sure embarrassed myself, huh?
（小関）
情けないとこ見られちゃったな
Are you sure it's a good idea to let
them do what they want like that?
（火ノ丸）いいんスか？
あんな連中に好き勝手させて
That's just how it is.
（小関）これが現状なんだ
No one can stand up to Yuma-san,
even though he's only a second-year.
まだ２年だけど
佑真さんには誰も かなわない
（火ノ丸）フン…　確かに空手の
心得は あるようじゃったがのぅ
True, he looked like he knew karate.
I'm impressed you noticed.
（小関）よく気づいたね
He actually won the Kanto
tournament in middle school.
なんでも
中学じゃ 関東大会優勝だって
That's fine, but where are
the other club members?
（火ノ丸）それはいいが
ほかの部員は おらんのか？
Well, as you can see, I'm the only member.
（小関）いや
見てのとおり 部員は俺１人だよ
Huh? The famous Ishigami High School
has only one member in their club?
（火ノ丸）えっ？
名門 石神高校が たったの１人？
Ishigami? This is Odachi High School.
（小関）
石神？　ここは大太刀(おおだち)高だけど
（火ノ丸）
はぁ？　ノォ〜！
Odachi High School Sumo Club
I thought for sure this
was Ishigami High School.
ワシは てっきり石神高校じゃと…
Most people would notice. Most would
come in through the front gate, too.
（小関）普通 気づくよね
…てか 入り口から入るよね
I messed up.
（火ノ丸）なんてことじゃ…
I see. That makes sense.
そっか　そうだよね
No one who wants to do sumo
would come to our school.
相撲をやろうって人間が
好んで ウチなんかに…
こっちこそ勘違いしてたよ
I messed up, too.
Sorry.
すまんのぅ
But it'd be a waste for a phenom like you
not to go to a real powerhouse school.
（小関）でも 君ほどの逸材—
ちゃんとした強豪に行かなきゃ
もったいないもんね
It's a waste for you as well.
（火ノ丸）
あんたこそ もったいないのぅ
（小関）えっ？
（火ノ丸）さっきの一番で分かった
I could tell from our bout.
Those legs and loins
その足腰は
地道な稽古を続けてきた証しじゃ
are proof you've been
diligently practicing.
Did you make that sumo ring?
あの土俵 あんたが作ったんか？
Oh, yeah.
The dirt is packed nice and tight.
（火ノ丸）
土はガチガチに固めてある
There are no weeds or pebbles.
雑草も小石も
きれいに取り除いとる
（火ノ丸）ウヘヘッ…
（小関）うん？
You're a sumo maniac, just like me!
あんたも ワシと同じ
相当な相撲バカじゃのぅ！
As long as you stick with sumo,
（火ノ丸）
あんたが相撲をやめんかぎり—
we’ll see each other
in a tournament someday!
いずれ
どこかの大会で相まみえるじゃろう
I'll be looking forward to it!
その時を楽しみにしとるぞ
Why...
なんで また
ダチ高に戻ってきとるんじゃ！
Why am I back at Dachi High?
Ishigami High
Supermarket
I had him draw me a detailed map.
詳しい地図描いてもらっといて
どうかしとるぞ ワシ
There must be something wrong with me.
I did all those things and
used up a precious day.
あんなことや こんなこと
しとるうちに貴重な１日を…
Odachi High School
Oh well. I'll thank him for
the map and go back home.
しゃあない
せめて 地図の礼でもして帰ろう
What happened?!
（火ノ丸）どういうことじゃ！
（小関）うん？
Ushio-kun...
潮君…
What happened to the sumo ring?
なんで土俵が こんなことに？
何があったんじゃ？
Who did this?
ウワッ…　俵もズタズタ…
The bale is in pieces, too...
I guess it's time to quit.
潮時 …かな
I can't do sumo at this school anymore.
（小関）この学校で
相撲を続けるのは もうムリだ
I didn't care if they called me lame or fat.
ダサいだの デブだの 何言われても
この土俵さえあればって…
As long as I had this sumo ring...
I could continue doing sumo.
相撲を続けてられる
I wanted to have a sumo bout here.
ここで いつか誰かと—
相撲が取れ…
（泣き声）
They even took that away from me.
それさえ… 奪われちまうのかよ
クッ…　ちくしょう！
（泣き声）
Damn it!
（西郷）いやぁ 肉体労働は大変だ
Manual labor is such a pain.
But it feels good to work up a sweat.
（橋）汗かくのって
意外と気持ちいいッスね
（佑真）フン！　お前が言うか
（火ノ丸）おい！
How would you know?
Hey!
That was heavy. What's in it?
重てえな　なに入ってんだ？
Aren't you ashamed of what you've done?!
お前　あんなマネして
恥ずかしくないんか！
God is watching!
（火ノ丸）お天道さまは見とるぞ
（佑真）はぁ？　何のことだよ？
Huh? What do you mean?
Don't play dumb!
You destroyed the sumo ring!
とぼけんな！
裏の土俵を壊したじゃろう！
Oh, so that's it.
あ〜 そういう…
こいつらがノリで やったんだろう
They must have gotten carried away.
You think that's good enough?
それで済むと思うとるんか？
ああ？
No, I'll obviously
take responsibility for them.
いいや　当然 ケツは持たねえとな
So, what would you have me do?
…で どうしてほしい？
A duel!
（火ノ丸）決闘じゃ
If I win, you give up the dojo.
ワシが勝ったら 道場は明け渡せ
A duel, eh?
（佑真）決闘ねえ…　いいぜ
Okay, but we’ll do it my way.
ただし
俺のやり方で やらせてもらう
（火ノ丸）かまわん
Fine by me!
That settles it.
決まりだ　よし 道場へ来な
Okay, come to the dojo.
おう　支度するから待っとれ！
Sure. I'm going to prepare, so wait for me.
Don't run away!
（佑真）逃げんなよ
（火ノ丸）誰が！
Who would?!
Ushio-kun!
（小関）潮君！
Don't worry.
心配いらん
これは ワシの個人的なケジメじゃ
This is my responsibility.
It won't be any trouble for you.
そっちの迷惑にはならんよ
That's not important right now!
そういうこと言ってるんじゃないよ
You don't know how scary Yuma-san is!
君は
佑真さんの恐ろしさを分かってない
There's no way he'll
make it a fair fight!
（小関）あの人が
正々堂々と決着つけようなんて—
思ってるわけないだろう
He'll use whatever he can to beat you!
君をつぶすためなら
どんな手だって使ってくる
Oh, they're nothing.
（火ノ丸）なぁに あんなヤツら
ワシは横綱になる男じゃぞ
I'm going to be a yokozuna.
Don't take them lightly!
茶化(ちゃか)すなよ！
君のために言ってんだぞ
This is for your own sake!
Stop talking about being a yokozuna!
“横綱 横綱”って
いいかげんにしろよ！
How tall are you, anyway?
大体 君 何センチなんだよ？
I know that you know this.
知らないなんて言わせないよ
You have to be at least 167 cm tall
大相撲の世界に入るには—
新弟子検査で
167センチ以上なきゃいけない
to pass the medical exam and
become a sumo wrestler.
You look like you're under 160 cm.
見たところ 160もないよね
I know you like sumo, but you
can't be a sumo wrestler,
相撲が好きなのは分かる
けど 君は横綱どころか
大相撲力士にすらなれない！
much less a yokozuna.
I shouldn't be the one saying this,
俺も 人のこと
言えた義理じゃないけど—
but there are things in this world
that can't be helped!
世の中 どうにもならないことって
あるんだよ！
I'm sorry I couldn't give you a bigger body.
（恵子(けいこ)）大きな体に
産んでやれなくて ごめんね
Anyway, you need to go.
（小関）とにかく 君は
このまま帰るんだ　いいね？　じゃ
Okay? Bye.
Like that matters!
そんなの関係あるか！
（舟木たち）ああ？
（佑真）よう　逃げずに よく…
Hey, so you didn't run.
What? Where's the shrimp?
なんだ　チビは どうした？
He's not coming.
（小関）あいつは もう来ません
（佑真）はぁ？
Please let this incident go.
今回の件
水に流してやってください
お願いします！
ああ？　あいつが
売ってきたケンカだろうが！
He asked for this fight!
Please! I'll do whatever you say!
そこを何とか！　俺なら
何でも言うこと聞きますんで！
Why, you...
てめえ　ふざけんじゃ…
If you'll do anything, then okay.
どうしてもってんなら いいぜ
Yuma-san.
佑真さん
You said you'll do whatever I say, right?
今 何でも言うことを
聞くっつったよな
Y-Yeah.
Give up sumo.
お前　相撲やめろ
アア…　でも そ… そんな…
But that's...
I don't know how you know him,
but you're here to protect him, right?
（佑真）
どんなつながりか知んねえが
体張って守ろうってんだろう？
Then you'd better be prepared
to lose something you value.
なら お前の大事なもん
捨てるぐれえじゃなきゃな
You're a sumo maniac, just like me!
（火ノ丸）
あんたも ワシと同じ—
相当な相撲バカじゃのぅ！
分かった
Okay.
フン…
I'll never again have a sumo―
俺は もう二度と 相撲は…
（殴る音）
いってえ！
Ow!
Don't talk like that.
（火ノ丸）
めったなこと言うもんじゃねえよ
Hey, I'm here.
（火ノ丸）よう 来たぜ
（小関）潮君！
Ushio-kun!
プッ！　なになになに？　その格好
Whoa, what's with that outfit?
（橋）
ハハッ！　お尻丸出しなんですけど
Your butt's hanging out!
He's exposing his body so we can hit it!
（舟木）
わざわざ防御力 下げてきやがった
Why are you here?! I told you to leave!
どうして？　あのまま帰れって…
I told you, this is my
personal responsibility.
個人的なケジメじゃ言うたじゃろう
Anyone who would abandon
you for their own gain
自分の将来のために
あんたを見捨てるようなヤツが—
could never become a yokozuna.
果たして 横綱になれるかね？
A yokozuna must have a strong spirit,
strong technique, and a strong body.
横綱ってのはよ “心技体”
全てそろわんと なれんのじゃ
しかし
ワシには 立派な“体(たい)”はない
Unfortunately, I don't have a large body.
So I can't let my spirit be weak, too.
その上
心まで失うわけにはいかんのじゃ
（小関）あっ…
（火ノ丸）だからさ
So...
Don't say you'll give up sumo.
相撲やめるなんて言わねえでくれよ
いやぁ お前の熱意に
すっかり心動かされちまったよ
Your speech really moved me!
いいね　じゃあよ その気持ちが
本物かどうか確かめさせてくれ
It was great.
So now let's see if your
spirit is the real thing.
You said we could do this
fight my way, right?
決闘は
俺のやり方でいいって話だったろう
（骨の鳴る音）
10分だ
Ten minutes.
10分間 無抵抗で殴られ続けて—
If you can endure ten minutes of punches
without fighting back, then you win.
最後まで立っていられたら
お前の勝ちでいい
Here comes the famous
Dachi High human sandbag!
（舟木）出た！
ダチ高名物 人間サンドバッグ
What kind of one-sided fight is this?!
（小関）
なんだよ そんな一方的なやり方！
Fine. Let's get started.
（火ノ丸）いいから さっさとやれ
（小関）ええっ？
Not going to back down even now?
この状況で そのスカした態度
ムカつくんだよ！
（殴る音）
You piss me off!
ヒイッ！
Hey...
おい　ちゃんと10分計っておけよ
You’d better be counting
those ten minutes.
Wh-Who are you?
な… 何なんだ？　てめえは
I am Ushio Hinomaru.
ワシは潮火ノ丸
My name will ring above the clouds
when I become a yokozuna.
雲の上にまで
その名をとどろかす—
大横綱になる男じゃ！
（佑真）あっ…
（火ノ丸）チンピラごときが…
Now, you petty thugs...
If you think you can beat me, bring it on!
倒せるものなら倒してみろよ！
（火ノ丸）退(ひ)くな　屈するな
Don't retreat. Don't back down.
This ring is only 4.5 meters across.
この直径 僅か15尺の
小さな円の中で—
I'm taking this body into fights where I lose
if one hand or knee touches the ground!
手をつくことも
膝をつくことも許されない—
そんな勝負に
このナリで挑もうってんだ
If I can't win now, then when will I?!
ここで勝てずに どこで勝つ！
（生徒１）おい 聞いたか？
Hey, did you hear? There's something
big going on at the sumo dojo!
相撲道場で
今 大変なことになってるぞ
The human sandbag again?
That's nothing new.
（生徒２）人間サンドバッグ？
いつものことじゃん
No, listen...
（生徒１）いや それがよ…
（生徒２）ウオッ…　マジか？
Are you serious?
（殴る音）
（佑真）この…　おら！　おら！
Why, you...
You!
この！　この！
（殴る音）
There!
おらぁ！
（殴る音）
Ow, damn it!
グッ…　いってえな　くそ！
何なんだよ！
What are you?!
Is time up?
（舟木）時間か？
（西郷）ウソだろう…
It can't be...
I added five minutes just to be safe.
念のため
５分 水増ししといたんだぜ
How...
（佑真）なんで…
（火ノ丸）おい
Hey.
That felt a little long.
Was it really ten minutes?
えらい長く感じたぞ
本当に10分か？
（佑真）なんで倒れねえんだ！？
（火ノ丸）ペッ…
Why haven't you fallen?!
What kind of stupid question is that?
なんでも くそもあるかい
In sumo, you lose if anything other than
the soles of your feet touch the ground.
相撲ってのは 足の裏以外が
地面に着いたら負けなんじゃ
I worked hard to make sure I won't fall.
倒れないために積んできた稽古じゃ
Those dull punches aren't
enough to drop me.
なまくらパンチで
ワシを倒せるわけなかろうが
There's no way that's true!
そんな理屈があるか！
Don't mess with me!
ふざけんじゃねえー！
I can fight back now.
無抵抗の時間は さっき終わったぞ
ガハッ！
It's time for some sumo.
（火ノ丸）
こっからは相撲の時間じゃ
Ready for a taste?
とくと味わえ
（佑真）ウオーッ！
（火ノ丸）はっきよい
Spirit!
H-He took Yuma-san down with one hit!
（小関）あ… あの佑真さんを
ぶちかまし１発で？
潮 …火ノ丸？
Ushio Hinomaru...
The two-time elementary school
champion from three years ago.
３年前の小学生相撲２連覇
He was so strong, they gave him the moniker
of a demonic national treasure:
その強さ 鬼のごとしと
恐れられた あの国宝—
“Onimaru Kunitsuna!”
“鬼丸国綱(おにまるくにつな)”
（小関）アア…
（火ノ丸）どうじゃ？
Well, understand how amazing sumo is now?
（火ノ丸）相撲は強いじゃろう
（佑真）ウウッ…
As promised, leave the dojo
key here and get lost.
約束じゃ　道場の鍵置いて うせな
You must be joking!
（西郷）ふざけんなよ てめえ！
You haven't won!
（舟木）こんなんで
勝った気になってんじゃねえぞ！
（火ノ丸）
ああ？　これは勝負じゃろうが
This was a duel.
We'll kill ya!
Stop!
（佑真）やめねえか！
I had fifteen minutes and
couldn't drop him,
俺が15分かけて倒せなかったのを
こいつは１発だぞ
but he did it in one hit.
I've lost, and that's all there is to it!
これが負け以外の何だってんだ？
Damn! How did I lose to that shrimp?
（佑真）
くそ…　こんなチビに この俺が…
If you want to know, try doing sumo.
（火ノ丸）
それが知りたきゃ相撲をやれ
I'm going to be the best
sumo wrestler in Japan.
ワシは 相撲で日本一になるんじゃ
You're welcome to challenge me
in the ring any time.
土俵の上でなら
いつでも受けて立つぞ
フン…
Odachi High School Sumo Club
（小関）アア…　道場が ついに
夢みたいだ
Finally, a dojo. It's like a dream!
It's not a dream.
（火ノ丸）夢でも何でもない
本来の姿に戻っただけじゃ
It's just gone back to
the way it should be.
Still, I can't believe you're
the national treasure, Onimaru...
（小関）それにしても
君が あの国宝 鬼丸だったなんて…
（火ノ丸）あんた 世の中 どうにも
ならんことがあるって言ったよな
You said there are things in
the world that can't be helped.
Y-Yeah...
I'm going to win, win more, and keep winning
（火ノ丸）
勝って勝って 勝ちまくって—
to show that it's not the size
of your body that counts.
体の大きさなんて関係ねえって
証明するために—
I'll be the best high school sumo wrestler
so that everyone knows about me.
高校相撲の頂点に立って
ワシの存在を知らしめてやるんじゃ
I'll make the professional sumo league
come and bow their heads to me.
それこそ 大相撲のほうから
頭下げに来るぐれえにな
It's strange. When you say it,
I feel like it might really happen.
不思議だな
君が言うと 本当に聞こえてくるよ
It's not something to joke about.
冗談で こんなことは言えん
See ya.
（火ノ丸）それじゃのぅ
（小関）ああ…
Please take one!
Come join the soccer club!
（サッカー部員）
サッカー部入ろうぜ サッカー部！
Oh, you want to join the basketball club?
The ball is your friend!
ボールは友達！
（サッカー部員）いてっ…
（小関）あっ ごめん
Sorry.
Quit shifting around.
（バスケ部員）
あんまチョロチョロすんなよ
Don't bother recruiting.
勧誘なんかしたってムダムダ
相撲部なんて誰も入んねえよ
No one's going to join your sumo club.
That's not true!
そんなことないよ！
I think.
多分…
But still...
…とは言ったものの
No, this is the year!
いやいや
今年こそは なんとしても！
（火ノ丸）
ウヘヘヘッ…　久しぶりじゃのぅ
Long time no see!
The dojo looks completely different!
（火ノ丸）道場も見違えたのぅ
（小関）
えっ？　潮君　なんで ここに？
Ushio-kun, what are you doing here?
There aren't many sumo maniacs like you.
（火ノ丸）あんたほどの相撲バカは
そうそうおらん
So I've decided...
決めたんじゃ　ワシは
あんたと一緒に天下を取るってな
You and I are going to dominate.
You and me?
俺と一緒に？
I'm counting on you, captain!
よろしく頼んます　部長！
ウオ〜ッ！　マジか！
ありがとう　本当に ありがとう！
You mean it? Thank you!
Really, thank you!
ウヘヘヘッ…
じゃ まず一番 お願いします！
Okay, let's have a bout.
Yeah, that sounds great!
（小関）うん 望むところだよ！
Really? But he's so small.
（生徒１）
マジで？　あんなちっちゃいのに
I'm sure of it.
（生徒２）間違いねえ　佑真さんを
入学前に倒したんだってよ
He beat Yuma-san before he enrolled.
You're famous already.
（小関）いきなり有名人だね
（火ノ丸）ンンッ…
Next Bout "Wrestling vs Sumo"
It's him...
あのときの…